翻校 Husky
资源 yoyo
压制 依依
不能再美!
It's amazing!
雪一直在下啊下的
The snow just keeps falling and falling!
我很开心你能和我们住在一起,老爸
I'm glad you're staying here with us, Dad.
我也很高兴,小子!
Yeah, me too, buddy!
这种暴雪天气待在车里实在太冷了
It's way too cold to stay in the van during this blizzard.
还有,车里的暖气也坏掉了
Besides, the heater in the van hasn't worked
大概是因为我装了那个迷你光碟播放器
since I got that sweet mini-disc player installed,
可是我一点都不后悔
which I do not regret.
我从来没有见过这么大的雪
I've never seen it snow like this before.
不完全对哦
That's not entirely true.
-怎么讲?-你是说那时候--
-Really? -You mean back when --
哦!
Oh!
那都是14年前事了!
That was about 14 years ago!
当时有一场暴风雪,就像现在这样
There was a snow storm happening just like this around then.
14年
14 years.
嘿,我也是14岁!
Hey, I'm 14 years!
是啊,小家伙,当时你只有几个月大
That's right, little man. You were only a few months old.
那时雪下得太大了
And it was snowing so hard,
我以为我们俩会变成雪人
I thought we were going to become Snowman
还有雪人它儿子,雪人二世
and Snowman Jr., son of Snowman.
刚好甜洋葱出城去看望家人
But Vidalia was out of town visiting family,
所以她就让咱俩在她家住了一段时间
so she let us crash at her place for a while.
那是你第一次--
It was the first time you --
老爸!!
Dad!!
我离你没那么远,史蒂文
I'm not that far away, Steven.
别忘了咱俩的...约定
Don't forget our... arrangement.
天了噜
Good gravy.
谁让你把我培养得喜欢音乐呢
That's what you get for raising me to love music.
幸运的是,我正好有一首歌适合这个故事
Luckily, I have a song for this story already.
♪在我生命里,在我生命里♪
♪ I could never be, I could never be ♪
♪你的出现我措手不及♪
♪ I could never be ready for this ♪
♪我措手不及,我措手不及♪
♪ I could never be, I could never be ♪
♪遇见生命中的你♪
♪ I could never be ready ♪
♪开篇和结局♪
♪ Things start, and things end ♪
♪在理论里多么甜蜜,但♪
♪ And isn't it lovely in theory, but ♪
♪我措手不及,我措手不及♪
♪ I could never be, I could never be ♪
♪遇见生命中的你♪
♪ I could never be ready ♪
♪♪
嘿 小史嘟宝
Hey, little Schtu-ball.
你在这儿跳什么舞呢
You're doing a lot of dancing in there.
你想出来展示下舞步是吗
You want to get out of there and show me your moves?
看看,你都把扣上的扣子弄开扣了
Hey, now. You unbuttoned all your buttons I buttoned up!
让我帮你扣上扣子
Let's get you buttoned back up.
马桑就吼
Ookie-pookie!
好了!哈?
There! Huh?
干嘛...
What's...
你的宝石还需要呼吸是吗?
Does your gem need to breathe?
嗯
Hmm.
这样怎样?
How about this?
哦!呃,你们几个好啊!
Oh! Um, hey, y'all!
-你好!-唷,格雷格,瞧瞧这个!
-Hello! -Yo, Greg, check it out!
我们给小玫瑰带了礼物!
We brought gifts for Lil' Rose!
紫晶,我跟你说过的
Amethyst, we've gone over this.
史蒂文是个--
Steven is a --
人类宝宝
Human baby.
还有史蒂文他...
And Steven is...
不是玫瑰
Not Rose.
你们需要点什么吗?
Can I get you guys anything?
我这儿有水,有旧盘子,还有...
We've got water, old plates, uh...
来点茶怎样?
How about some tea?
不用。我们只是来放下这些礼物的
No. We're just here to drop off these gifts.
哦对!当然了
Right! Sure.
这个给你
Here you go.
你可能得帮他拆开
You'll probably have to open that up for him.
这个盒子
It's just a box,
只是看起来像包装过了一样
made to look like it's been carefully wrapped.
谢谢你,石榴,但是我不觉得他用得上这个
Thanks, Garnet, but I don't think he needs this.
哦,他会用得上的...在未来
Oh, he'll need it... in the future.
下一个是我的礼物!
Let's open mine next!
哇!尿布!真是实用呢!
Wow! Diapers! This is so practical!
等下 这些是成人纸尿布?!
Wait. Are these adult diapers?!
对他来说太大了
They're way too big for him.
那就告诉他把自己变得大一些!
So tell him to make himself bigger!
你能做到对吧,小格雷格?
You can do that, right, Lil' Greg?
你可以叫他史蒂文
You can call him Steven.
这是我和玫瑰最喜欢的名字
That's the name Rose and I liked the most.
嘛,不管你叫他什么,他会用得到这个的
Well, whatever you call him, he'll need this.
呃,谢谢 这是什么儿童图书吗?
Uh, thanks. This some kind of kid's book?
哦 是本词典
Oh. A dictionary.
很显然,这是最好的礼物
Obviously, it's the best gift
最合适没有沟通能力的生物
for a being that can't yet communicate.
你们可以用它来查一下婴儿是什么意思
Well, maybe you guys could use it to look up what a baby is.
这些礼物都很棒
These gifts are great,
但是史蒂文太小了用不到这些
but Steven's just too young for this stuff.
现在,他最喜欢这个
Nowadays, he's really into this.
♪钥匙链 ♪
♪ Carabiner ♪
♪钥匙链!♪
♪ Carabiner! ♪
哇!他真的喜欢!
Whoa! He loves it!
嘿,小-史蒂文!
Hey, Lil' -- Steven!
嗯,他真的被这东西迷住了
Hmm. He's certainly captivated with those things.
这样,下次我们就给他
Well, next time, we'll just bring
带一盒子钥匙就好了
a big box of keys for Steven.
发生什么事了?!
What's happening to him?!
是玫瑰I!
t's Rose!
这真的有可能吗?
Is that possible?
他会变成一束激光吗?!
Is he gonna turn into a laser?!
放轻松,你们几个 我已经想明白了
Relax, y'all. I got it all figured out.
玫瑰正在试着变回原来的形态!
Rose is trying to shape-shift back to her old self!
-啥?!-她现在变不回来
-What?! -She can't shape-shift
因为她被这个宝宝困住了!
because she's trapped in a baby!
被宝宝困住?
Trapped in a baby?
玫瑰?
Rose?
玫瑰,是我,珍珠!你在里面吗?
Rose, it's me. It's Pearl! Are you in there?
是的话就闪两下!
Glow twice for yes!
宝宝别闹,我正试着和玫瑰说话呢
Baby, please. I'm trying to talk to Rose.
玫瑰没有变形,她也不是被困住
Rose hasn't shape-shifted, and she isn't trapped.
史蒂文是个融合体
Steven is a fusion.
玫瑰是在试着解开融合
Rose could be trying to unfuse.
不管史蒂文是什么,现在有状况发生了
Whatever Steven is, something's happening,
而我--我能帮上什么?!
and I -- What can I do to help?!
这个,人类婴儿发光的时候你都怎么处理啊?
Well, what do you do with a human baby when it glows?
首先,人类婴儿不会发光
First off, human babies don't glow.
然后其第二个次...
And letter number "B"...
要是会发光怎么办啊?!
what if they do?!
不慌,甜洋葱那有些关于宝宝的书籍我有在读
Okay, Vidalia has some books on babies I've been reading.
读书会给我们些头绪的
They'll help us figure something out.
冷静,你能做到的
Calm down. You got this.
各位,如果是类似发烧的症状的话,我们该--
Guys, if this is anything like a fever, then we should --
呃,人呢?
Uh, guys?
人呢?!
Guys?!
你们拐走了我?!
You kidnapped me?!
对头!
Yep!
我们有些行动确实有点令人后悔
Some of our actions were a bit regrettable.
当时,我们以为用自己的方式来解决
At the time, we thought it'd be better
会比较好一些
to handle things our way.
管他呢 我们就直接拐了你
Nah. We straight-up 'napped you.
史蒂文!我的车!
Steven! My van!
把宝宝还给我!
Give me back my babies!
他看着很生气啊
He looks mad.
他以后会感谢我们的
He'll thank us later.
格雷格一直以来都很努力
Greg was doing his best up to this point.
但是现在情况变了
But the situation has changed.
史蒂文显然是个宝石人
Steven is clearly a gem.
还好我们没有解释就跑了
Good thing we left without any explanation.
好了,玫瑰,我们看到你发光了
All right, Rose, we saw that glow.
所以你为什么还是个宝宝?
So why are you still a baby?
是因为很有趣还是怎么的?
Is it... really fun or something?
石榴,抱着我!
Garnet, hold me!
好吧,我懂你了
All right, I get it.
这感觉简直太棒
This rules.
但是你已经这样很长时间了--都几个月了!
But it's been so long -- like months!
这比我变成马桶那次都长
That's longer than I was a toilet.
别这样,玫瑰!
Come on, Rose!
你该变回来了!
You have to change back!
宝宝 正常
Baby. Normal.
宝宝...
Baby...
这多容易啊!
It's so easy!
为什么她就不肯变呢?
Why can't she do it?
因为她不是在变形
Because it's not shape-shifting.
她在融合
It's fusion.
史蒂文,我明白你的一部分是格雷格变的
Steven, I understand Greg is part of you,
你不想在他面前解开融合
and you don't want to unfuse in front of him.
因为会很不礼貌
That would be very rude.
但是现在他没在这儿了
But he's not here now.
就只有我们而已!
It's just us!
你可以休息一会儿了
You can take a little break.
这样,我也来解开
Here. I will, too.
我还在这儿!
I'm here!
你认识我的!你也认识她们!
You know me! You know them, too!
我不明白!
I don't understand!
史蒂文!
Steven!
我该怎么追上她们?
How am I gonna catch up with them?
狗
Dog.
雪橇
Sled.
狗,雪橇
Dog, sled.
嘿!嘿,孩子们!
Hey! Hey, you kids!
大家冷静下来
Everyone, calm down.
看,我们都能看到她
Look, we can all see her.
她就在这儿!
She's right there!
她不能变形回来是因为
She just can't reform because
她被这个宝宝...包住了
she has this... baby around her.
玫瑰,我知道你在里面
Rose, I know you're in there.
我可以放你出来
I can let you out.
我们能再次相聚
We'll be together again.
我做不到
I can't.
我做不到!
I can't!
她太想要这样了
She wanted this so much.
我实在搞不懂为什么!
I just don't understand why!
“万物都应生长,万物都应改变
"Everything should grow, and everything should change.
最--最棒的是
And -- And isn't it so great
这对于人类而言这多么自然”
how it comes so naturally to humans."
这对于我们来说不自然啊!
Well, it's not natural for us!
这对于我来说...不自然啊
It's not natural...for me.
对他来说...
It will be...
是自然的
for him.
可是玫瑰呢?
What about Rose?
这不是关于玫瑰的
This isn't about Rose.
从现在起,所有事都应该是关于
From now on, everything has to be
史蒂文的
about Steven.
救---我!
He-l-l-l-l-p!
救我!
Help!
呃 谢谢
Ugh. Thanks.
嘿,等下!
Hey, wait a minute!
你们为什么要在暴雪的天气
Why did you take Steven on a joyride
带史蒂文自驾游?
in the middle of a blizzard?
你们这是要干什么啊?
What's the big idea?
我们也没想好什么主意
There wasn't really a big idea.
就是一些凑不到一起的零碎的想法
Just a bunch of small ideas that never came together.
是我的不对,格雷格
My apologies, Greg.
我以为我们知道史蒂文是什么
We thought we knew what Steven was.
可是我们不知道
But we didn't.
说实话,我也不确定我懂
Honestly, I'm not sure if I do, either.
我从小时候起就没有发光过
I never glowed when I was a kid.
我们就没有小时候
We never were kids.
我不知道我们该怎么搞明白这些
I don't know how we're going to figure this out,
但是我觉得如果我们一起来的话
but I think we'll have a better shot
至少会更好一些
if we do it together.
哇 你们几个真的搞错了所有事
Wow. You guys were wrong about everything.
这个,这件事已经--
Well, that was a --
过去了很长时间了,不是吗
A really long time ago, wasn't it?
别对我们要求那么高,好不?
Cut us some slack, will ya?
我们当时不知道该怎么做,甚至是我
We couldn't have known what to do, even me.
特别是我
Especially me.
不,我是说改变和成长
No, I mean about changing and growing,
还有你对于你们来说不自然那些话?
and how it doesn't come naturally to you?
但是看看你们现在的样子!
But look at you now!
我知道你们一直都在怀念妈妈
I know you'll never stop missing Mom,
但是我想她会爱死现在这样的
but I bet she would've loved this.
我就是
I do.
-同意-同意
-Hear, hear. -Hear, hear.
当时有个女孩绑架了史蒂文
It wasn't such a big deal
那也不是什么大事对吧
when that teenaged girl kidnapped Steven.
那个是史蒂文的临时保姆
That was his babysitter.
她带史蒂文去公园玩
She took him to the park.
你们把攀爬架往她身上扔的时候真的把她吓到了
You really scared her when you threw that jungle gym at her.
♪♪